I'll answer your question...
You wanted to know why I'm here?
I came to take you, Yatori,
from this land without a future.
A Stormy Encounter
Ikta.
Ikta!
Wake up, Ikta!
What do you want, Kus?
You're boarding a ship to go to an island,
so you can't just run
there at the last second!
Lady Yatori!
Are you headed for the
high-level officer exams?
Yes. I haven't seen all of
you since our graduation.
Her relatives live in the east of Katjvarna.
The eastern garrison is fighting
the Kioka Republic's invasion, right?
They're having a hard time
with the new enemy forces,
but the garrison's commander is the famous
Lieutenant General Hazaf Rikan.
Every hero dies from overwork.
You should get those
relatives out of there.
That place is going to fall to the
Kioka army in less than a month.
Ikta Solork?
Hey, what do you mean by that?
Exactly what I said.
Lieutenant General Rikan's
garrison is fighting
with everything they have right now!
A defeatist like you would never
understand, though, would you?
You've got me there.
How dare you!
Now, now.
Calm down, everyone.
It's almost time, so I must get going.
I'm relieved that you actually showed up,
and also that you didn't
slack on the first exams.
Well, you said you'd get me
an easy job as a librarian
at the national library with
your family connections.
So, you think it will fall?
The garrison may have defense,
but they're not an offensive threat.
All because the emperor and cabinet have
no real intention of going to war—
That's enough.
Still, asking me to take the second exam
and rig it so you do well?
It's pretty sneaky, and totally unlike you.
As the eldest daughter of the Igsem family,
I need the honor of passing
at the top of my class.
I hear that my rival in this race
is the Remeon family's youngest,
so it's best to be cautious.
Yeah, yeah, I'll do my best.
This is the last time I want to
have anything to do with the army.
Right. That's the kind of guy
you've always been.
Igsem?
Like the Field Marshal?!
M-My name is Haroma Becker.
This is my partner, the water spirit Mil.
It's nice to meet you,
Ms. Igsem and Mr. Solork.
People using my family name
makes me queasy,
so just Yatori is fine.
In that case, please call me Haro.
As you wish, Haro.
You're trying to become a combat medic?
That's exactly right.
Embarrassingly enough, this is
my third attempt at the exams.
Ikta Solork.
What are you doing here?
So you passed, too?
Matthew Tetdrich.
His partner is the wind sprite Tsu.
He also went to school with us.
If you've heard of the Tetdrichs,
let him know.
It'd make him very happy.
What kind of introduction is that?!
Whether one's heard of us or not,
we Tetdrichs have been a distinguished
military family for generations!
T-Tetdrich, is it?
Um, I think I've heard of it,
or maybe not...
Oh, come on, Matthew.
We can't tell if you're famous or not,
and that's the perfect position for you.
It's not like comedians need
to be known everywhere.
Um... Is Ikta from
a noble family, as well?
Who're you calling a comedian?!
Solork is the name of an orphanage.
Not only am I a commoner,
I don't even have a father or mother.
I was found passed out
on the roadside
by Kus, who used to work at
the Solork Orphanage at the time.
I'm so sorry...
Please call me Ikky,
as a mark of our friendship.
O-Okay... Um, my hand...
Oh? It appears that your
fingers are a bit rough.
Do you do housework often?
I have five younger brothers,
and I'm the oldest sister...
Please don't pinch my ear lobe!
Please leave my hair alone!
Try to pick up girls
some other time, Ikta.
Are you all right?
Ikta has this bad habit.
If you don't stop him,
he'll fondle your boobs
and try to take you to bed.
B-Boobs?!
It looks like I'm in this room, too.
May I come in?
Of course you can't.
Huh?
Go back to your own turf, pretty boy.
Please, come in.
We were all just introducing ourselves.
My name is Torway Remeon.
This is the wind sprite Saphy.
Pleased to meet you.
It's a difficult exam,
but let's all do our best.
I see... So you're...
I'm Yatorishino Igsem.
This is Shia, my partner.
That's all I need to say, isn't it?
I see. That flame-colored hair...
You're the Igsem family's eldest!
Don't get cocky, you two.
The Igsem infantry and
the Remeon gunners
aren't where it's at anymore!
Don't get haughty because
your families are famous!
Um, who are you?
Matthew Tetdrich!
Don't forget that name,
youngest of the Remeons!
I'm good at remembering people's names.
Can I call you Matty?
Huh?!
And you are?
There's no need for two hunters
at one hunting ground.
You were brought before appearance court,
and they declared you guilty!
The charges were:
being too sexy!
Uh...
It is written in the scriptures
of the Aledelans...
Suffer not a hottie to live!
That could get you tried
for heresy, you know.
This is Ikta Solork.
He habitually tries to scare off
any handsome man he sees.
Don't let it bother you.
Are you two friends?
We've just known each other
for a long time.
Nice to meet you, Ikta.
May I call you Ikky?
Nope!
She's the only one who can call me that.
Huh? Me?
Her name is Haroma Becker.
She wants to command a medic squad
and has five younger brothers at home.
She's a very good girl. I guarantee it.
Th-That introduction's likely to
cause a misunderstanding...
I see.
I get it now.
What do you "get"?
Solork!
Now that we've finished our introductions,
let's make ourselves at home.
Damn it! I lost again!
Why did I lose?
Um, I think it was...
Twenty-one moves ago,
my dear friend Matthew.
When you forced your riflemen
into the enemy lines.
You memorized the whole match, Ikky?
You can't even see the board from there.
Don't call me that!
Tea's ready, everyone.
It's rocking a lot.
Thank you, Yatori.
So you're playing Military Chess, huh?
How many times did Matthew lose?
Why are you assuming I lost?!
Does it matter?
A master chess player isn't
necessarily a master general.
That's right.
And if actual soldiers are playing,
it should be blindfolded chess.
Ikky, why is th—
No calling me Ikky!
In a real battle,
can a general get a
bird's-eye-view of the battlefield?
No, most of the time he has to estimate
the location of the enemy
based off limited information.
Even the soldiers under his command
may not faithfully execute his orders.
That's right.
What a soldier needs is imagination,
which allows him to use fragmented
information to envision the whole.
Blindfolded chess can at least
create the base for that.
Have some tea before it gets cold.
Thank you, Haro!
Ow, that's hot!
Is someone there?
Are you okay?
You don't look like
you're here for the exam.
E-Excuse me!
There shouldn't be any
civilians aboard this ship.
What do you think, Ikta?
Five to six years before
she's ready to eat,
and maybe fifteen before
she's fully ripe?
I wasn't asking about
your personal preferences.
Wh-What was that?
Grab only what you really need
and head to the deck.
Obey the sailors' orders
and get on the lifeboats!
Everyone, stay calm and move forward.
Did we really run aground?
Seriously?
What a terrible storm.
So, who's got the bad karma?
Get the ones here on the lifeboats!
You, without question.
Okay, lower it!
Y-You're kidding me!
In this storm?
Matty, get to the right.
And Becker, to the left.
Yatori, that's the girl.
That's not good. She's going to die.
Kus, if you can still see her,
light her up with your high-beam.
Ikta, it's dangerous.
Please.
Ikta?
If you let go, I'll come back to haunt you.
Hey, Ikta!
That's crazy!
Ikky!
Oh...
Am I going to die here?
I still have things to accomplish...
Are you awake?
Who are you?
Princess, forgive us for
meeting you in such a manner.
Raise your heads.
Tell me what's going on.
As you wish.
The six of us barely made it
on a lifeboat in time,
and now we have sought refuge
in a cave by the sea.
I see.
It wasn't a dream, after all.
You kept me warm, then?
Haroma Becker and I, Yatorishino Igsem,
did so without your permission,
but we were left with no choice.
We beg your forgiveness and mercy.
A-And mercy!
I am deeply grateful for your kindness.
You said your name was
Yatorishino Igsem, correct?
Yes, ma'am.
It was eight years ago when I visited
your home along with the emperor.
You remembered?
You were only four years old then...
And you were ten.
You didn't recognize me.
Your growth surpassed my expectations.
If not for the Eternal Spirit Tree's ring,
I wouldn't have been sure.
Indeed.
I am the third princess
of the Katjvarna Empire,
Chamille Kitra Katjvanmaninik.
Where are the others?
They've gone out to
survey our surroundings.
P-Princess,
my name is Matthew Tetdrich.
May I-I... speak?
Your family commands
a garrison in Ebdorck, right?
Speak freely.
I-If you've sufficiently warmed,
may I have my jacket back?
Oh, my apologies.
Ah, d-don't!
You're in your underwear
right now, Princess.
What was a princess doing on our ship?
I think it's better not to pry into
the imperial family's matters.
You'll end up a mess,
and that's if you're lucky.
Still, I'm impressed.
The ship was about to sink,
and you still brought that along.
You mean the air rifle?
It's my third most important belonging,
after my comrades' lives and Saphy.
Anyway, I'm hungry.
No way...
Even if we were swept by
the currents, we can't be...
We can see the empire's eastern border
to the west from our position.
Which means...
This is Kioka Republic territory, then?!
We're in enemy territory?
I think it's important that
we're all on the same page now.
We've got two choices:
One, surrender to the Kioka army,
and ask to be treated as prisoners of war.
That one's pretty safe.
The other is to break through the border
and return to the empire.
That one's a gamble.
Even if we're taken prisoner,
our safety is assured, right?
That's being too optimistic.
There are people here who can be
used as diplomatic bargaining chips.
Not just the princess,
but Yatori and Torway, too, right?
Well, basically, even if
we're taken prisoner here—
Never.
I will never be taken prisoner!
I don't have time to waste here.
We must break through
the borders, no matter what.
I'll give you any reward you—
Shut your mouth for a moment, Princess.
No matter how much you scream,
you won't make the impossible possible.
Imperial history alone should be enough
to teach you tha—
Your Highness, I'm terribly sorry.
Please, forgive him just this once.
He was the one who jumped
into the sea to save you.
You were...
Th-That's enough.
Let him go.
You're right. I'd lost control of myself.
Be thankful for Her Highness's mercy,
and go outside to calm yourself a little.
Sure thing.
That's not like you.
The Ikta Solork I know is a sarcastic ass,
but he never gets worked up like that.
I didn't think that just because she's
a member of the imperial family
it would be so infuriating
to see her lose control.
So that was it.
I thought I'd given up
on it long ago, though.
This may be rude to say,
but Princess Chamille is acting her age.
That's right.
She's only lived two-thirds
as long as I have,
so why am I expecting so much from her
just for being part of the imperial family?
Oh, can I borrow your main gauche?
Chip it, and I'll kill you.
It's been two days since
I've had a real meal!
Not bad, considering we just
grabbed what we could find!
We can't have a constructive discussion
on an empty stomach.
Yup.
I got a huge haul today,
even if I do say so myself.
The meat is so good!
My air rifle is...
Princess.
As for what we do now,
it's true that my cries
will make no difference.
We cross the border by ourselves,
or surrender and become prisoners of war.
I want you to think long and hard
before making a decision.
The princess is right.
They won't find us easily here.
We can take a day or two to think.
All set here.
Next is...
Is there anything I can help with?
No, there's no need.
Please, relax.
I-I see.
Your air rifle has a long barrel.
I need to aim as far as possible.
Solork, is there anything I can do?
Can you help me?
I'm weaving these.
A net?
No, something that's a much bigger
necessity for a human lifestyle.
Is this a bed?
A navy-style bed.
It's called a hammock.
It's great once you get used to it.
Try it out!
Wow!
You got on it all right.
C-Can you really sleep on these?
Try relaxing.
I see.
This is indeed very relaxing.
A good day starts with a good bed!
Solork, what's that?
That's a blimp.
A Kioka air unit.
Kioka's new weapon, the one that caused
massive damage to the eastern region?
Yes,
but it's alone, which means
it's on a scouting mission.
We'll head into the caves for
a while so it doesn't find us.
I can't take it anymore.
I'm not used to doing it outside...
Is someone there?
Wake up, everyone.
Something's tripped the warning line.
Torway, get your weapon ready.
I'm ready whenever.
Huh? Where's the princess?
If we don't come back,
surrender to them immediately.
What's wrong, Irick?
I heard something over there.
If someone's there,
put your hands up and come out.
We have guns.
There!
Hey, stop right there!
Solork?
Year 905 on the Imperial Calendar.
This man, Ikta Solork,
would later come to be known
as the Invincible Lazy General.
Next time: "An Unwanted Medal of Honor."
An Unwanted Medal of Honor.